# **Cristian Carlos Vargas**

# Front-End Software Engineer

Elmwood Park, IL 60707
Phone: (773) 706-5634 | Email: <u>cristian.v0223@gmail.com</u>
<u>LinkedIn</u> | <u>Github</u> |
Portfolio

## **SUMMARY**

I am a Javascript Developer specializing in Front-End Technologies and Frameworks such as React, and Next.js. I am passionate about Design Systems, Web Accessibility, and Serverless Technologies such as Google Cloud. To further sharpen my skills, I focus on building and maintaining full stack web applications using a variety of technologies and frameworks.

#### **SKILLS**

Languages: HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Typescript,

Database Systems: MySQL, Postgresql, Sequelize, MongoDB, NoSQL, Mongoose, Prisma

Tools/Frameworks: React.js, Next.js, Node.js, Express.js, Bootstrap, Tailwind, Web/Server-Side/Third-Party API's,

Insomnia, Netlify, Heroku, Vercel, Firebase, Mongo Atlas, Git, Wordpress.

#### **PROJECTS**

#### Nextflix

Built an application mirroring the UI of Netflix using Next.js, Node.js, React, Typescript, Tailwind, Google Firebase, and Vercel. Using the TMDB API (The Movie Database API) users are able to browse a selection of movies ranging from Netflix Originals, Top Rated, Horror, Comedy, Action-Thriller, and Trending after signing up and creating an account.

Deployment | Repository

## Yelpcamp

Built a user review and recommendation application for campgrounds in the United States using Mapbox API, EJS, Node.js, Express.js, Bootstrap, and MongoDB. The user is able to see all the campgrounds coordinates on a map, scroll through a list of campgrounds, read a brief description of a campground, see photos of a campground, add a new campground, delete a campground the user created, and review/rate campgrounds they have visited before.

<u>Deployment</u> | Repository

#### **EDUCATION**

Northwestern University — Full Stack Coding Bootcamp Certificate, Chicago, IL March 2022 - Sept 2022

Triton College — Associate's of Arts (AA), General Studies River Grove, IL January 2018 - May 2022

#### **CERTIFICATIONS**

**UDEMY**— The Web Developer Bootcamp 2022, Certificate, Online March 2022 - November 2022

#### PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

MARKETING ANALYST

Magnolia Capital

November 2022–Present

Chicago, IL

- Create, format, and maintain website content for both National Home Rentals and HighVine Homes using HTML and Wordpress.
- Audit and maintain National Home Rentals and HighVine Homes online profiles using Google Analytics.

- Audit National Home Rentals and HighVine Home's listings on ILS feeds such as Google, Yelp, Zillow, Redfin, and Apartments.com
- Assist with creating internal and investor reporting primarily through Airtable for marketing analysis reports.
- Integrated Airtable and Google Sheets and wrote automations to create a more efficient workflow between Magnolia and our media vendor Shoootin.
- Create, format, and maintain marketing materials including presentations, badges, and fliers following the National Home Rentals and HighVine Homes brand guidelines.

#### LISTING COORDINATOR

August 2022–November 2022 Chicago, IL

Magnolia Capital

- Collaborates with the Sales and Maintenance team, including in person and virtual meetings, to ensure the listing process for all homes are being completed as expected.
- Maintain the photos, description, and amenities for all National Home Rentals and HighVine SFR rental homes on the MLS, and on the company's proprietary software Propify.
- Update the status of all National Home Rentals and HighVine SFR rental homes accordingly during the rental lifecycle.
- Order photos for newly purchased homes with media vendor Planomatic Inc.

CLIENT SPECIALIST May 2022–July 2022

First Look Appraisals LLC

Chicago, IL

- Managed broker and lender profiles, while communicating appropriate resolutions to all client correspondence not limited to emails or calls on: refunds, reassignments, lender changes, turntime requests, escalated orders, order troubleshooting, and report transfers.
- Successfully doubled the idle time of the operations team of 3 by exceeding the 100 support ticket goal, and answering 20% of all inbound calls daily.
- Maintained an ethical barrier between the mortgage broker, appraiser, and borrower during the appraisal lifecycle in correspondence with USPAP and AIR.

VENDOR MANAGER Feb 2022–May 2022

Appraiser Vendor LLC

Greenwood, IN

- Managed unassigned appraisal orders in my region, and assigned them to local appraisers on panel, or to new appraisers that need to be onboarded.
- Communicated and negotiated daily with appraisers in my region to assign them appraisal orders to complete within our client's budget and timeframe.
- Managed expectations of client's whose files are escalated, defining any recourse the company can provide including reassignment or refund if necessary.

# APPRAISAL COORDINATOR

Jan 2021–Jan 2022

First Look Appraisals LLC

Chicago, IL

- Managed escalated and unassigned appraisal orders in California and Arizona, and assigned them accordingly to local appraisers approved on our panel, or to new appraisers that need to be onboarded.
- Exceeded the assigned orders goal daily in my region increasing the idle time for the Vendor Solutions team using effective and concise communication with appraisers.
- Increased the idle time of the Digital Solutions and Status Solutions teams by exceeding the 100 support ticket goal, and answering all inbound calls with no voicemails left daily.
- Maintained an ethical barrier between the mortgage broker, appraiser, and borrower during the appraisal lifecycle in correspondence with USPAP and AIR.